<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>At Stirling the 12. of June 1645</title>
            <author>Scotland. Parliament. Committee of Estates.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1645</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B05248</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S1240A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R183984</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">51617458</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 51617458</idno>
            <idno type="VID">175358</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B05248)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 175358)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2730:28)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>At Stirling the 12. of June 1645</title>
                  <author>Scotland. Parliament. Committee of Estates.</author>
                  <author>Primrose, Archibald, Sir, 1616-1679.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By Evan Tyler, Printer to the Kings most excellent Majestie,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Printed at Edinburgh :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1645.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Text begins: Forsameikle as the Committee of Estates taking to their serious consideration, the many practices and endeavours used against this kingdom, by some unnaturall countrey-men and traitors, joyned with Irish rebels within the same ...</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Signed at foot of text: Arch. Primerose.</note>
                  <note>An act for a new levy.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Scotland. --  Army --  Recruiting, enlistment, etc. --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Scotland --  History --  Charles I, 1625-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  Scotland --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-12</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-12</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-01</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="document">
            <pb facs="tcp:175358:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <opener>
               <dateline>At <hi>STIRLING</hi> 
                  <date>the 12. of June 1645.</date>
               </dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">F</seg>Orſameikle as the Committee of Eſtates Taking to their ſerious conſideration, The many practices and endeavours uſed againſt this Kingdom, by ſome unnaturall Countrey-men and Traitors, joyned with Iriſh Rebels within the ſame; And by the Armies that are preparing in Ireland and England for ſubverſion of Religion, did by their Act of the 28. of March laſt, give warning thereof to the Shires, That they might have their Forces in readineſſe upon advertiſement. And the Committee now finding the dangers that threaten this Kingdom, ſtill to continue, and a preſsing neceſsity of the raiſing of ſome Forces for ſtreng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thening the Armies, and enabling them to encounter their Enemies abroad. And being confident, That all who are zealous of Religion, the honour of their Native Countrey, and their own ſafety, will heartily concurre herein: And rather ſend out their own Forces to meet the Enemie, nor lye ſtill while the Countrey be over-run, and themſelves, and their Families deſtroyed at their own Doors; Have therefore thought fit, Statute and Ordained, That the whole Shires under-written, and Burrows within the ſame, and Committees of Warre thereof, Shall preſently leavy and raiſe the number of men following, and have them in readineſſe, furniſhed with eight dayes proviſion: And that they deliver them to theſe Officers that ſhall come from the Generall, to receive them for making up of their Regiments, betwixt and the 4. of July next, under the pains contained in the Acts made concerning the former Lea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vies, and farther to be eſteemed and cenſured as betrayers of the Kingdom and Cauſe in hand. The numbers to be as follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth: The Sheriffdoms of Roxburgh and Selkirk, 1000 Foot, whereof 400. for recruting Colonell <hi>Scots</hi> Regiment: 400. for the Earle of Lowthians Regiment in England: And 200. for the Maſter of <hi>Cranſtouns</hi> Regiment: The Sheriffdom of Ber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wick, 600. Foot, for recruting <hi>Wedderburne</hi> and <hi>Aitouns</hi> Regiments, according to the numbers they formerly had out of that Shire: The Sheriffdom of Hadintoun, 600. Foot for the Lord Humbies Regiment, except the Maſter of Yeſters proporti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, which he is ſtill to have out of theſe Bounds he had his firſt Leavy: The Sheriffdom of Edinburgh principall, and Baillierie of Lauderdaile, 600. Foot for the Earle of Lauderdailes Regiment, except the Maſter of Yeſters proportion out of theſe Bounds he formerly had: The Town of Edinburgh, 600. Foot for Colonell <hi>Raes</hi> Regiment: The Sheriffdom of Peebles, 200. Foot for the Maſter of Yeſters Regiment: The Sheriffdom of Lithgow, 250. for the Earle of Callenders Regiment: The She<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riffdom of Dumfreis, 600. for Kalheids Regiment, except the Maſter of Yeſters proportion thereof: The Sheriffdoms of Wigtoun and Kirkcudbright, except the Earle of Caſſils diviſion thereof, 600. Foot for the Vicount of Kenmure, and Colonell <hi>Stuarts</hi> Regiment equally betwixt them: The Sheriffdom of Air and Renfrew, 1000. Foot, whereof 600. out of Kyle and Cunninghame, for the Lord Chancellours Regiment, 200. out of Renfrew for Glencairnes Regiment, and 200 out of Carrick for Caſsils Regiment: The Sheriffdom of Lanerick, 750. for the Generall of Artilleries Regiment: The Sheriffdom of Fyffe, 1200. Foot, for the Earle of Crawfurd, Dumfermlings, and Elchoes Regiments, according to their former proportions, al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing what Forces they have already put out by publike Warrand beſide the former Leavies: And for the Leavies of the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manent Shires, Recommends to the Committee of Eſtates in the North to give orders therefore. And the Committee of Eſtates do farther recommend to the whole Gentlemen and Heretors of the Kingdom, To have their whole Forces Horſe and Foot in readineſſe, to march to the Borders upon advertiſement: And to be the more carefull in putting out this Leavy, that the Publike are content for eaſe of the Shire, to bear the Burden of furniſhing Arms to thir Forces.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Arch. Primeroſe.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed at <hi>Edinburgh</hi> by <hi>Evan Tyler,</hi> Printer to the Kings moſt Excellent Majeſtie. 1645.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:175358:2"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
